Guide to the Frick Fine Arts Department Chair Records, 1920-1986 UA.90.8.16.2
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Frick Fine Arts Department Chair Records
1920-1986
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Department of Fine Arts
UA.90.8.16.2
8.75 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
The University of Pittsburgh Fine Arts Department was founded in 1926 through a gift from Helen Clay Frick. This collection contains files documenting the administration of the Frick Fine Arts Department through the records of several of its chairs, including Walter Read Hovey and William Loerke.
History
The University of Pittsburgh Fine Arts Department was founded in 1926 through a gift from Helen Clay Frick. Dr. Frederick Mortimer Clapp was named the first chair of the department and he began his term by traveling to Europe to select books, photographs, and lantern slides to serve as the foundation of a fine arts library. The department and library were initially located in State Hall and instruction began in September 1927. Upon the completion of the Cathedral of Learning, the department relocated to its seventh floor.
In 1966 the Frick Fine Arts Building was completed near the entrance of Schenley Park, funded again through donations by Helen Clay Frick. The new building included classrooms, faculty offices, a concert hall, museum galleries, and the library. Once in the Frick Fine Arts Building, the number of faculty and students in the department grew. An Andrew W. Mellon Professor of Contemporary Art History and Theory and a Post-Doctoral Fellowship were also established to attract top art history scholars to the university. In 1994 the name of the department was changed to the Department of History of Art and Architecture.
Scope and Content Notes
These records contain files documenting the terms of several chairs of the Frick Fine Arts department, primarily Walter Read Hovey, William Loerke, and Donald Gordon, spanning between 1920 to 1986. The files largely represent the general administration of the department, the Frick Fine Arts Library, and exhibitions. Included are correspondence with prospective faculty and students, as well as art scholars and professionals. Also present are memoranda, meeting materials, and correspondence with University of Pittsburgh administrators and local art organizations.
Access Restrictions
Due to the confidential nature of the records in Series V, files will be closed for a period of 75 years from their date of creation.
Universities and colleges -- Departments -- Records and correspondence; College department heads -- Correspondence; Correspondence; Administrative records; Student records; University of Pittsburgh. Department of Fine Arts -- Records and correspondence; Hovey, Walter Read, 1895-1981; Loerke, William C.; Gordon, Donald E.; Williams, John, 1928 February 25-2015; Linduff, Katheryn M.; Frick, Helen Clay, 1888-1984; Frick Fine Arts Library; Frick Fine Arts Building (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Walter R. Hovey, 1920-1965; I.
  Biography
  Walter Read Hovey (1895-1981) joined the University of Pittsburgh in 1928, first serving as an Assistant Professor for four years until being promoted as a Professor within the Fine Arts Department. Originally from Springfield, Massachusetts, Hovey obtained his undergraduate degree in English from Yale University and his master's degree from Harvard University in Art History. Later in life, Hovey obtained an honorary Doctor of Fine Arts degree from Wooster College in Ohio.
  Hovey developed a close friendship with the department's benefactress Helen Clay Frick during his time at the University of Pittsburgh. When the department's first chair, Frederick Mortimer Clapp, left to oversee the new Frick Collection in New York City in 1936, Hovey was named his replacement. He served as chair until 1963 when he was awarded the Henry Clay Frick Professorship of Fine Arts and named a Professor Emeritus at the university. The position was created by Helen Clay Frick to keep Hovey involved in the construction of the new building for the fine arts department after he reached the age of retirement. This position was terminated after Hovey left the university on April 15, 1967.
  After Pitt, Hovey joined Point Park College and served as the Advisor for Asiatic Art at the Carnegie Museum of Art. Hovey also served as a consultant and lecturer at the Pittsburgh Frick Art Museum, which Helen established after her separation from the University of Pittsburgh.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains files from Walter Read Hovey's administration as chairman of the Frick Fine Arts Department. Included are memoranda and correspondence with several University of Pittsburgh administrators, including Chancellors John Bowman and Edward Litchfield and Dean Stanton Crawford. Hovey's friendship with the department's benefactress, Helen Clay Frick, is also apparent in their letters and his involvement in the development of a catalog for the Frick Collection in New York. Much of the correspondence with prospective faculty and students and other scholars in the art community is organized alphabetically by the name of the correspondent or their organization.
  - Ad-Al Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Am Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Art, 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - An-Av Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports - Fine Arts and College, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art Dealers, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ba Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Be Correspondence, 1940-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bi Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Biddle, Theodore W. - Dean of Men and Chancellor's Reception Committee Chair, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biddle, Theodore W. - Pitt Johnstown, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bo Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bowman, John G. - Chancellor, 1949-1956 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    This file includes correspondence between Bowman, Hovey and Helen Clay Frick regarding the financial status of the Frick Fine Arts Library as well as a proposed plan for the future of the department.
  - Bu Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget Information and Correspondence, 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Budget Information and Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ca Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ch Correspondence, 1940-1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ci-Cl Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Civil Affairs Training School - First Aid Protection for Art Treasures and Monuments (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Co Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - College Art Association, 1940-1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - College Art Association, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - College Art Association, Higher Education and Visual Arts Questionnaire (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Competitions, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Core Curriculum in the Humanities, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cr-Cu Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Crawford, Stanton C. - Dean of the College, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Crawford, Stanton C. - Dean of the College, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Crawford, Stanton C. - Dean of the College, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Crawford, Stanton C. - Dean of the Faculties, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Da-De Correspondence, 1940-1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Di-Du Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Directives for Graduate School, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Directives for Graduate School, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    This file contains information on postdoctoral research fellowships and memos to graduate faculty.
  - Directives, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Directives for Students, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Division of the Humanities, 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - E Correspondence, 1940-1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Eastern Book Company, 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Educational Continuum, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Edwards George and Company, 1953-1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Exhibit Pamphlets, University of Pittsburgh, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - F Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - F Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Faculty, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Faculty Biographical Information, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Fedel, Arthur - Administrative Assistant, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Fine Arts Program Information, 1920-1957 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fine Arts Society, 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Foundations, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Frick Collection Catalogue, 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Frick Collection Catalogue - Chinese and French Ceramics, 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Frick, Helen C. and the Frick Collection, 1940-1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Frick, Helen C. and the Frick Collection, 1948-1953 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Fundraising, United Fund, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ga-Gl Correspondence, 1940-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Gallery Coverings, Wall-Rus Fabrics Co., 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Geise, Dr. John, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Geise, Dr. John, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Go-Gu Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Faculty, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Faculty Membership Nomination (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Programs, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ha Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - He-Hi Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Heath, Roy - University Counseling Center, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ho-Hu Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Honors Convocation, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Honors Program (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hovey, Walter R. - News articles, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hovey - Indian Trip, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - I Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Interdepartmental Correspondence, 1940-1957 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ja-Je Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Jalbert, Russell - Public Relations, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Jo-Ju Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Jones, Putnam - Dean of Graduate Faculty, 1951-1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jones, Putnam - Fellowships and Grants, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Ka-Ki Correspondence, 1940-1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Kehl, James, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Kl-Ku Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - La-Le Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Lecturers, 1940-1953 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Li-Ly Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Litchfield, Edward H. - Chancellor, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Litchfield, Edward H. - Chancellor, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Litchfield, Edward H. - Chancellor, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Liu, James - Far Eastern Studies, 1954-1960 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Luccock, Emory W. - University Chaplain, 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Ma Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Mc Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - McKibbin, Mary A. - Art Director, Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1952-1962 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Meetings, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Mi Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Mo-My Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Mosaics - Glass Orders, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Na Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Ne-Nu Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Ob-Ol Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Om-Ox Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - One Hundred Friends of Pittsburgh Art, 1952-1958 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Pa-Pe Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Peake, Charles - Vice Chancellor, 1957-1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Personnel Division, 1957-1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Memoranda, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ph-Pu Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photograph Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Physical Education, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Physical Plant Memoranda, 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Plan for Art, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    The Pittsburgh Plan for Art is a non-profit community art program and this file contains meeting notes, information releases, and correspondences specifically with Hovey.
  - Pittsburgh Views, 1940-1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Planning and Urban Development, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Planning and Urban Development Proposal, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Playhouse Association, 1947-1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Prospective Purchases, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Psychological Warfare Section, Far East Command - Leaflet Propaganda, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Publicity - News Articles, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Purchasing Department, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Q Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ra-Ri Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Rankin, Alan C., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Ray, Charles - Security, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Registrar, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Registration, 1933-1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Religion in Life Week, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Reynolds, Carroll - University Extension Division, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Ro-Ry Correspondence, 1940-1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Sa Correspondence, 1940-1958 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Salary Memos and Budget Requests, 1941-1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Sc Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Scholarships and Awards, 1949-1959 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Scholarships and Fellowships, 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - School of Education, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Se-Sl Correspondence, 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Sm-Sp Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - St-Sy Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - T Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Teachers' Insurance, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Travel, 1960- 1962 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Trimester Plan, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - U Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - University Press, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - University Senate, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - University Senate, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - V Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Vieh, W. F. - Assistant Chancellor, Business Affairs, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Wa-We Correspondence, 1940-1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Wadsworth, Frank W. - Dean of the Humanities, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Weber, John - Secretary of the University, 1935-1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Wedekind, Carl - Director of Educational Planning (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Wh-Wr Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Witman, Shepherd L., 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Wittenborn and Co., 1940-1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1961-1963; 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - X-Y-Z Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Young, Arthur - Classics (Box 5, Folder 12)
- William C. Loerke, 1959-1974; II.
  William C. Loerke (1920-2014) served as Chairman of the Frick Fine Arts Department from June 1964 to 1969 when he returned to the teaching faculty. During Loerke's time as chair he struggled with Helen Clay Frick over control of the department, with the benefactress taking a hands-on role in the hiring of faculty and other decision making.
  Loerke obtained a bachelor's degree from Oberlin College in classical archaeology and his Master of Fine Arts and doctorate degrees from Princeton University. After earning his Ph.D., Loerke served on the faculty at Brown University as the Regional Selection Committee of the Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation. Following his time in Rhode Island, Loerke taught at Bryn Mawr College as an associate professor before coming to the University of Pittsburgh to succeed Hovey as chair of the Frick Fine Arts Department. After leaving the University of Pittsburgh, Loerke was appointed professor of Byzantine art and director of studies in the Byzantine Institute at Dumbarton Oaks Research Library and Collection where he remained until retiring in 1988.
  This series contains correspondence, reports, and memoranda pertaining to the Frick Fine Arts Department during William C. Loerke's term as chairman. Much of the correspondence with colleagues, prospective students, and community members was organized by the department into chronological files. Topics of interest within this series include the completion of the Frick Fine Arts Building, management of the Frick Fine Arts Library, and the development and administration of the Mellon Student Art Study Travel Program.
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Directives, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Arts and the Small Community, Wisconsin Idea Theatre, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Asian Studies Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Baldwin Seminar, Oberlin College, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Bucci Detective Agency, Building Security, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Campus Food Services Availability Booklet, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Chronological Correspondence, September-November 1965 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Chronological Correspondence, December 1965-March 1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Chronological Correspondence, April-July 1966 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Chronological Correspondence, August-December 1966 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January-April 1967 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Chronological Correspondence, May 1967 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Chronological Correspondence, June-July 1967 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Chronological Correspondence, August-September 1967 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Chronological Correspondence, October 1967 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Chronological Correspondence, November 1967 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Chronological Correspondence, December 1967 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January 1968 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Chronological Correspondence, February-March 1968 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - College Art Association of America, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Committee on the International Dimension Program, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Committee to Rescue Italian Art (CRIA), 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Committee on Russian and East European Studies, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Course Descriptions (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Curator of Photographs Job Search, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Department Faculty Activities Reports, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Department Proposals, 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Department Staffing, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Departmental Teaching Assignments and Enrollment, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Division of the Humanities Department Chair Meeting Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Ecuador Project, Annual Report, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Equipment Inventories, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Faculty Applicants, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Faculty Applicants, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Faculty, Graduate Students, Assistants, and Teaching Fellows, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Fine Arts Mellon Chair Search, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Fine Arts Seminars, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Frick Fine Arts Building Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Frick Fine Arts Building, Event Requests, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Frick Fine Arts Building, Keys and Security, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Frick Fine Arts Building, Physical Plant Requests, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Frick Fine Arts Building, Telephones (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Frick Fine Arts Graduate Program, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Frick Fine Arts Graduate Student Lists, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, Collection Management, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, Osborne Report on Spending, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library Staff, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Friends of the Fine Arts Department, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Gow, J. Steele - Learning Research and Development Center (LRDC), 1964 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Policy Committee, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Program, Requirements and Deadlines, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Student Organization Newsletter (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Grieder, Terrence - University of Texas, 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Halliday, David - Dean, Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Higher Education Acts, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Honors Committee and Courses, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Index of Christian Art, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Insurance, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Inter-American Foundation for the Arts, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - International Dimensions Faculty Seminars, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jefferson, Blanche - School of Education, Art Education, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Kress Foundation Graduate Fellowship Proposal, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kuspit, Donald, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Latin American Art Historian Search, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Lecture Series, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - London Grafica Arts, Inc., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Martin, Albert - Dean, Liberal Arts, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Mellon Book Fund, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mellon European Seminar Expenses, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Mellon Fellowships, 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Mellon Fellowship Applicants, 1964-1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Mellon Professors, 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Mellon Professors, Prospective, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Mellon Professor Search, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Mellon Student Art Study Program Grant, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Mellon Student Art Study Travel Grant, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Mellon Student Art Study Travel Grant, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Mellon Student Art Study Travel Grant, January 1968 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Mellon Student Art Study Travel Grant Expenses, October-December 1967 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Minnott, Charles I. - Fine Arts Professor, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Mounting and Handling of Prints, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Pittsburgh Arts Council Steering Committee, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Posvar, Wesley W. - Chancellor, Directives and Memos, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Printing Requisitions, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Prospective Faculty, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Prothmann, Dr. Konrad, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Salary Memos, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Schleier, Erich - Prospective Mellon Fellow, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Scholarships and Fellowships (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - School of Liberal Arts Academic Assembly, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - School of Liberal Arts Honors Committee, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Seminar - Opportunities and Techniques for Research Abroad in Art History, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Seymour, Charles - Mellon Professor, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Slatkes, Leonard J. - Fine Arts Professor, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Slides and Slide Storage, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Spence, Robert - Fine Arts Professor, 1962-1965 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Student Charges and Tuition, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Student Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Student Employment, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Swarthmore College Honors Exams, 1962-1966 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Tuition Fellowships, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - University of Pittsburgh, Greensburg, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - University Senate Minutes and Meetings, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - University Senate Meetings and Minutes, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 56)